A Guide to the Elizabeth Jacquelin Ambler Papers, 1780-1832
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg
Elizabeth Jacquelin Ambler Papers, 1780-1832.
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
DMS 54.5
25 items.
Elizabeth Jacquelin Ambler Brent Carrington, 1765-1847
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Deposit, 1954.
Alternative Form
Also available on microfilm (M-1120) and as a transcript (TR/53)
Biographical/Historical Information
Elizabeth Jacquelin Ambler Brent Carrington (1765-1847)was the eldest daughter of Jacquelin and Rebecca Burwell Ambler.
Scope and Content Information
Correspondence from Elizabeth Jacquelin Ambler Brent Carrington, includes letters to her friends, Mildred Smith Dudley of Yorktown, Virginia, and Frances Caines of Bristol, England. These letters, Elizabeth's own copies of the originals, describe her family's difficulties during the American Revolution; the sudden death of her first husband; and the unfortunate life of one of her childhood friends. Later letters to her sister, Ann Ambler Fisher, are Eliza's attempts to describe their family and its antecedents; their life in Yorktown before the Revolution; the hardships of their flight from the British; and the changes the war made in their lives. Included are sketches of their parents and their brother-in-law, Chief Justice John Marshall. Some passages on her later life explain why she retained these letters. Also included is Eliza's copy of an 1815 letter from John A. B. Fisher to his mother, discussing his parents' reaction to his desire to become a minister.
Arrangement
Chronologically arranged.
Index Terms
Family Names:
Ambler family.
Persons:
Carrington, Elizabeth Jacquelin Ambler Brent, 1765-1847.; Caines, Frances.; Dudley, Mildred Smith.; Fisher, Ann Ambler.; Fisher, John A. B.; Marshall, John, 1755-1835.
Geographical Names:
United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783--Women.; United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783-- Refugees.; Yorktown (Va.)--History--Revolution, 1775-1783.
Contents List
- Mildred Smith [Dudley] to Eliza Jacquelin Ambler, 1780.
- Eliza Jacquelin Ambler to Mildred Smith [Dudley], 1780.
- Eliza Jacquelin Ambler to Mildred Smith [Dudley], Richmond, 1781.
- Mildred Smith [Dudley] to Eliza Jacquelin Ambler, 1782.
- Eliza Jacquelin Ambler to [Mildred Smith Dudley], Richmond, February, 1785.
- Eliza Jacquelin Ambler to Mildred Smith [Dudley], 10 July 1785.
- Eliza Jacquelin Ambler to Mildred Smith [Dudley], Williamsburg, 10 January 1786.
- Eliza Jacquelin Ambler to Miss [Frances] C[aines], Bristol, 1786.
- Eliza Jacquelin Ambler to Miss [Frances] C[aines], 1792.
- Eliza Jacquelin Ambler to Miss [Frances] Caines, Bristol, Richmond, March, 1795.
- Essay on family, [Eliza Jacquelin Ambler to Ann Ambler Fisher], 10 October 1796.
- Eliza Jacquelin Ambler to Miss [Frances] C[aines], 1802.
- Eliza Jacquelin Ambler to Ann [Nancy] Fisher, 1 January 1807.
- Eliza Jacquelin Ambler to Ann Fisher, [1807-1809]
- Eliza Jacquelin Ambler to Nancy [Fisher], 1809.
- Eliza Jacquelin Ambler to [Ann] Nancy [Fisher], March, 1809.
- Eliza Jacquelin Ambler to [Ann] Nancy [Fisher], 1810.
- Eliza Jacquelin Ambler to [Ann] Nancy [Fisher], November, 1810.
- Eliza Jacquelin Ambler to [Ann] Nancy [Fisher], [1810]
- J. A. B. Fisher to Mother [Ann Fisher], Yale College, 1 May 1815.
- Eliza Jacquelin Ambler to Frances Caines, Richmond, November, 1820[6]
- Eliza Jacquelin Ambler to [Ann] Nancy [Fisher], 11 March 1823.
- Variety or the Vicissitudes of Life, 7 pp., n.d.
- Binding, n.d.